let quiz = [
    {
        question:
            'How many pollen grains will be formed after meiotic division in ten microspore mother cells?',
        options: ['10 ', '20', '40 ', '80'],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Flowers showing ornithophily show few characteristic like',
        options: [
            'blue flower with nectaries at base of corolla',
            'red sweet scented flower with nectaries',
            'bright red flower into thick inflorescence',
            'white flowers with fragrance',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which type of association is found in between entomophilous flower and pollinating agent ?',
        options: [
            'Mutualism',
            'Commensalism',
            'Cooperation',
            'Co-evolution',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which is the most logical sequence with reference to the life cycle of angiosperm ?',
        options: [
            'Germination, endosperm formation, seed dispersal, double fertilization',
            'Cleavage, fertilization, grafting, fruit formation',
            'Pollination, fertilization, seed formation & germination',
            'Maturation, mitosis, differentiation',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Tapetum is',
        options: [
            'parietal in origin usually the inner most layer of anther wall.',
            'modified endothecium of anther wall.',
            'modified outer most layer of sporogenous tissue.',
            'parietal in origin and is the inner most layer of ovule wall.',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following pair has haploid structures?',
        options: [
            'Nucellus and antipodal cells',
            'Antipodal cells and egg cell',
            'Antipodal cells and megaspore mother cell',
            'Nucellus and primary endosperm nucleus',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Male gametophyte of angiosperms/monocots is',
        options: [
            'Microsporangium ',
            'Nucellus',
            'Microspore ',
            'Stamen',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The type of cells under going meiosis in the flowers are',
        options: [
            'micro spore mother cell & mega spore mother cell',
            'ovule & stamen',
            'tapetal cells',
            'placental cell',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which ones produces androgenic haploids in anther cultures?',
        options: [
            'Anther wall',
            'Tapetal layer of anther wall',
            'Connective tissue',
            'Young pollen grains',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Generative cell was destroyed by laser but a normal pollen tube was still formed because',
        options: [
            'vegetative cell is not damaged',
            'contents of killed generative cell stimulate pollen growth',
            'laser beam stimulates growth of pollen tube',
            'the region of emergence of pollen tube is not harmed',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The embryo is carefully taken out of pea seed and sown in the soil and watered normally. New plant will',
        options: [
            'be healthier ',
            'be weaker',
            'not be formed ',
            'be formed normally',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Pea seeds are sown in a pot. After emergence of cotyledons, the pot is placed in an aerated dark chamber and watered normally, seedlings will',
        options: [
            'form normal plants',
            'form healthier plants',
            'die',
            'grow very rapidly without forming leaves',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'If there are 4 cells in anther, what will be the number of pollen grains ?',
        options: ['8 ', '4', '16 ', '12'],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'A cutting of rose plant is thoroughly waxed and planted in the soil normally, it will form',
        options: [
            'new rose plant.',
            'a dead piece of rose stem after some time.',
            'a rose plant of improved variety.',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'In angiospermic plant having chromosome number of 12 will have chromosome number in integuments and nucellus of',
        options: ['4 ', '6', '12 ', '24'],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the fate of the seven cells of the embryo sac ?',
        options: [
            'All but one disintegrate upon fertilization.',
            'Two become fertilized; the others disintegrate.',
            'Two become fertilized; the others fuse to form endosperm.',
            'All are involved in nuclear fusion events.',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'The most common type of pollination is –',
        options: [
            'entemophily',
            'ornithophily',
            'malacophily (by snails)',
            'chiropterophily (by bats)',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'When an ovary develops into a fruit, without fertilization, it is called',
        options: [
            'apospory ',
            'apogamy',
            'parthenocarpy ',
            'porogamy',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following has largest gametophyte ?',
        options: ['Oryza ', 'Funaria', 'Pinus ', 'Selaginella'],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Exine of pollen is formed by activity of',
        options: [
            'tapetum ',
            'endothelium',
            'middle layers ',
            'endothecium',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which of the following statements about pollen and pollination is false ?',
        options: [
            'Evolution of the pollen grain rejected the need for swimming sperm in flowering plants.',
            'At maturity, the pollen grain consists of two sperm nuclei and a tube nucleus.',
            'The pollen tube enters the female gametophyte through the style.',
            'The pollen grain makes twice the genetic contribution to endosperm cells than it does to the cells of the embryo.',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following options is correct?',
        options: [
            'Pollination gives the guarantee of the promotion of postpollination events that lead to fertilization.',
            'The events – “from pollen deposition on stigma until pollen tubes enter the ovule” are together referred to as pollen-pistil interaction.',
            'Pollen-pistil interaction is a dynamic process involving pollen recognition followed by only promotion (not rejection) of the pollen.',
            'Pistil has no ability to recognise the pollen, whether right or wrong type.',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Cross-pollination is preferred over self-pollination because',
        options: [
            'it results in better offspring.',
            'the new varieties are formed.',
            'it is easy.',
            'parthenogenesis can be induced.',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'Seminiferous plant is',
        options: [
            'having only staminate flowers.',
            'reproducing by seeds.',
            'reproducing by vegetative propagation.',
            'None of the above',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which is the correct order of events for female gametophytes?',
        options: [
            'Megagametophyte; megasporocyte; megaspore',
            'Megagametophyte; megaspore; megasporocyte',
            'Megasporocyte; megaspore; megagametophyte',
            'Megaspore; megasporocyte; megagametophyte',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
];
